<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Fresh Start</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Fresh Start</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Fresh Start</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Getting more information</title>
      <link>/info/more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/info/more/</guid>
      <description>Please contact us if you would like some more information about Fresh Start and its programs.
Restricted topics Information is available on certain restricted topics.
By clicking this link I acknowledge that I want to view the restricted topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Restricted topics</title>
      <link>/restricted/restricted/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/restricted/restricted/</guid>
      <description>We are not permitted to make this information available without your express consent. Please leave this page unless you wish to view restricted topics.
 Topic 1 Topic 2  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 1</title>
      <link>/restricted/topic1/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/restricted/topic1/</guid>
      <description>This topic is not yet written.
Return to restricted topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Topic 2</title>
      <link>/restricted/topic2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/restricted/topic2/</guid>
      <description>This topic is not yet written.
Return to restricted topics.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Careers</title>
      <link>/careers/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Oct 2017 20:33:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/careers/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start Recovery Programme is committed to solving the world’s addiction problems and you can be part of this vision. Join a dedicated team helping families with addictions. We are a not-for-profit organization operating within a Christian ethos offering generous salary packaging in a friendly and supportive working environment. Current opportunities
 Administration Assistant (closed August 16th) General Practitioner Registered Nurse Team Leader (closed August 16th)  Application Instructions For more information about these opportunities and instructions on how to apply, click on the position title and download a Job Application Package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northam Recovery Centre</title>
      <link>/contact/nrc/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:25:33 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/nrc/</guid>
      <description>Phone: (08) 9621 2691
Email: nrc@freshstart.org.au</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Start Wish List</title>
      <link>/support/wishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:19:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/wishes/</guid>
      <description>Small Items for Northam Recovery Centre  Art supplies for the residents to use (e.g. paint, card, paint brushes).  Small Items for Harborne House  Board games Toiletries for patients (toothbrushes, toothpaste, soap, shampoo, deodorant) Non-perishable food items Bedding (e.g. doonas, doona covers, sheets, pillows, pillow cases).  Big Items for Harborne House  TV new kitchen.  Please contact us if you would like to donate any of these or if you have any other items you think would be useful to Fresh Start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer</title>
      <link>/support/volunteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:18:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/volunteer/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start Recovery Programme is committed to excellent service to both our clients and the wider community. Delivering this service would not be possible without the help of our committed volunteers.
Among the valuable services our volunteers provide are:
 helping care for patients during their detox period helping transport patients assisting with administrative duties in the office preparing food for patients on treatment days taking part in busy bees to freshen up and maintain the residential housing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invite Us To Visit</title>
      <link>/support/visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:18:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/visit/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start would be delighted to visit your community group or church or come to a gathering in your home. We have a number of presentations that are suitable for different settings, such as:
 “Help us to help families with addictions” (a fundraising talk by our CEO) “Helping families avoid addictions” (presented by one of our senior staff) “Why do children from good families still get addicted?” (presented by one of our doctors).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Bequest</title>
      <link>/support/bequest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:18:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/bequest/</guid>
      <description>By making a bequest to Fresh Start Recovery Programme (a Deductible Gift Recipient and Registered Health Charity), you can help us to continue our work beyond your lifetime, offering a lasting contribution towards recovery from addictions and rebuilding families. Your bequest will play a vital role in supporting our treatment and rehabilitation services or ongoing research into development and improvement of medical procedures for addictions. When you include us in your Will, you are offering the gift of hope and a Fresh Start to some of the most vulnerable people in our community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donate</title>
      <link>/support/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:18:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/donate/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start greatly appreciates the generous support we receive from individuals, the business community and various organisations. We are only able to continue our work through partnerships with organisations and individuals. Together we can offer a Fresh Start and the gift of hope for a drug-free future.
All donations over $2 are tax-deductible.
There are several ways you can offer financial support:
 Monthly Donation Make a monthly gift to Fresh Start and you will help heal families and individuals who have been torn apart by addictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northam Greeting Cards</title>
      <link>/support/cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:18:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/cards/</guid>
      <description>Residents at Northam Recovery Centre are creating unique, hand-made greeting cards as part of the Northam Art Program. These original art works can be used for any occasion!
Cards are for sale for $3.50 each or 10 cards for $30 plus packing and handling. (This includes envelopes.) Please contact the Northam Recovery Centre to order cards.
All funds raised go towards supporting the Northam Art Program as well as various leisure activities and excursions for residents on the road to recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Us</title>
      <link>/support/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:08:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/support/</guid>
      <description> Northam Greeting Cards Donate Make a Bequest Invite Us To Visit Volunteer Fresh Start Wish List    I wondered why somebody didn&amp;rsquo;t do something. Then I realized, I am somebody. &amp;ndash; Lily Tomlin
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Alcohol</title>
      <link>/info/alcohol/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 12:02:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/info/alcohol/</guid>
      <description>Alcohol harm The Australian National Drug Strategy Household Survey found that over 80% of the population drinks alcohol. Not all of this is harmful, but 10% of people drink alcohol in a way that risks long-term harm and 21% drink at least once a month in a way that risks short-term harm. Excess alcohol is capable of damaging nearly every organ and system in the body.
Alcohol use is also a major cause of deaths in Australia.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Amphetamines</title>
      <link>/info/amphetamines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 12:02:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/info/amphetamines/</guid>
      <description>What are amphetamine-type stimulants? Amphetamine type stimulants (ATS) include amphetamines, methamphetamine, MDMA (ecstasy) and dexamphetamine. They work by increasing levels of serotonin, dopamine and norepinephrine in the brain:
 Serotonin is involved in controlling anger, aggression, body temperature, mood, sleep, sexual feelings, appetite and metabolism. Dopamine is involved in behaviour and thought, movement, motivation and reward. It also inhibits prolactin production which is involved in lactation, sleep, mood, attention and learning.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Benzodiazepines</title>
      <link>/info/benzodiazepines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 12:02:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/info/benzodiazepines/</guid>
      <description>Benzodiazepines include diazepam (Valium), alprazolam (Xanax), midazolam, oxazepam (Serepax), temazepam and nitrazepam (Mogadon). Benzodiazepines are prescription drugs and many people who have become addicted to them did so after a doctor prescribed them.
Benzodiazepines reduce anxiety. However, people who use them for some time often find they need higher and higher doses to achieve the same effect. This is because prolonged use makes the receptors in the brain that detect them less sensitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Information</title>
      <link>/info/information/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 12:02:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/info/information/</guid>
      <description>Opiates Amphetamines Benzodiazepines Alcohol More   Fresh Start patients include people who are dependent on various substances and, frequently, a combination of more than one substance.
Please contact the clinic for more information about substances and their effects.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Opiates</title>
      <link>/info/opiates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 12:02:29 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/info/opiates/</guid>
      <description>Opiates and opiate antagonists Opiates, including heroin, methadone, opium, morphine and codeine, work by binding to the opioid receptors in the brain. The opioid receptors also detect the body’s own naturally-occurring chemicals such as endorphins. Opiates are drugs derived from opium. There are also a number of synthetic opioids including methadone and buprenorphine.
When a person regularly uses a drug like heroin or morphine, the opioid receptors in the brain become much less sensitive.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Beliefs and Values</title>
      <link>/about/beliefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:34:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/beliefs/</guid>
      <description>The Fresh Start Statement of Belief embodies a primary commitment of the organisation: Good Christian teaching.
Our Christian Beliefs  The Nature and Character of God We believe in one God, who has existed forever as Father, Son and Holy Spirit in a community of pure and eternal love.
 The Creation of Humanity Men and women were created in God&amp;rsquo;s likeness with God-given dignity and worth in order to know, love and serve him forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Statement</title>
      <link>/about/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:34:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start Recovery Programme (&amp;ldquo;Fresh Start&amp;rdquo;) is legally bound by the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). We are committed to protecting and securing the privacy and confidentiality of your personal information.
Fresh Start must apply the National Privacy Principles in Schedule 3 of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) that came into effect on 21 December 2001. These principles relate to collection, use, disclosure and security of your personal information, as well as access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Board</title>
      <link>/about/leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:34:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/leadership/</guid>
      <description>G.A.D (Sandy) Clarkson - Chairman Sandy is an Accountant with a private CPA Accounting Practice. He has worked in the private sector for most of his life with stints in the WA State Government and in Local Government as Councillor and Deputy Mayor of the town of Mosman Park.
He has been associated with Fresh Start Recovery Programme for almost 15 years as a volunteer, Director and Chairman.
Alison Petrie Alison is the Managing Director of professional conference management company, EECW Pty Ltd based in Nedlands WA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Approach</title>
      <link>/about/approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:34:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/approach/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start’s approach to helping people with addictions is sometimes known as the PHREE model:
 Physiology Housing Relationships Education Employment  Physiology Our programs treat the physical cravings of drug addiction. Our follow up and other medical services such as our GP Clinic and Hepatitis C program support the general health of patients.
Housing Many drug users who come to Fresh Start depend on other users for a place to live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GP Clinic</title>
      <link>/services/gp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:22:07 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/gp/</guid>
      <description>Make an appointment to see one of our doctors.
All Fresh Start patients have access to general health services through our GP clinic. The GP clinic is open four days a week (Mondays, Tuesdays, Thursdays and Fridays). In addition to this, patients have access to counselling, mental health and chaplaincy service, and are able to make an appointment on any of these days. Our Hepatitis C treatment clinic usually takes place on Tuesdays.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Chaplaincy</title>
      <link>/services/chaplaincy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:14:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/chaplaincy/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start has a team of chaplains who, upon request, provide chaplaincy and spiritual care for patients and their families. Our rehabilitation program is based on Christian beliefs and values. It uses a Christian version of ‘The Twelve Steps’ in conjunction with The Life Recovery Bible.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Counselling</title>
      <link>/services/counselling/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:14:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/counselling/</guid>
      <description>The Fresh Start Recovery counselling team consists of four professionally trained staff (male and female) providing a range of services and approaches geared toward individuals, couples and families.
Our service helps people address their substance use and the impact it may be having on their lives. Alcohol and other drug use can adversely affect relationships, health, work, mental state and other areas of life. Counselling aims to help people with addictions to focus on underlying issues that have previously contributed to continued drug use and subsequent relapse.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis C Treatment</title>
      <link>/services/hct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:14:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/hct/</guid>
      <description>Make an appointment to see our Hepatitis C Specialist Nurse.
What is hepatitis C? Hepatitis C is a viral illness that damages the liver and is caused specifically by the Hepatitis C virus (HCV).
Currently, in Australia, one person in every hundred has the Hepatitis C virus, and there is no vaccine for Hepatitis C. HCV infection is classified as an epidemic world-wide.
The virus is spread by blood-to-blood contact so you can get the Hepatitis C virus if an infected person&amp;rsquo;s blood comes into contact with your own.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Housing</title>
      <link>/services/housing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:14:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/housing/</guid>
      <description>Our patients go through several stages in recovery and their accommodation needs can change at each stage. We believe providing these residential facilities helps prevent our clients slipping back into drug use.
Harborne House Harborne House is a short term safe environment for patients in acute stages of pre- and post-detoxification and recovery. Twentyfour hour care and medical assistance is provided.
Transitional Housing Fresh Start has limited transitional housing available for clients.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mental Health Care</title>
      <link>/services/mhc/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:14:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/mhc/</guid>
      <description>Make an appointment to see one of our Psychologists or Mental Health Nurses.
Psychology Services Fresh Start psychologists offer a more specialised approach to dealing with problems of addiction. Our psychologists have a comprehensive understanding of behavioural and mental processes and offer a range of techniques to address client issues. Please note that sessions with our psychologists are limited in number, however our counsellors and mental health nurses are able to provide longer term support to individuals and families.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Rehabilitation</title>
      <link>/services/rehabilitation/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:14:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/rehabilitation/</guid>
      <description>Northam Recovery Program Fresh Start has two residential rehabilitation properties for men located in Northam. Our program is a Modified Therapeutic Community model in which the community itself is the principal means for promoting personal change through self-help and mutual support. Residents begin their journey at Northam Recovery Centre, graduating to The Hill when ready.
Northam Recovery Centre This three story building located in Northam has sleeping quarters for up to 40 men, common areas, garden area, chicken shed and vegetable patch.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Groups</title>
      <link>/services/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:14:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/support/</guid>
      <description>Getting free from drugs offers you a fresh start, but it&amp;rsquo;s just the first step&amp;hellip;
Take this opportunity to change your mindset, expand your community, connect with people who care, share your wisdom, and support others on the journey.  Fresh Start Community Groups Fresh Start Community Groups (Recovery Circles) are for people in recovery, carers and supporters. There&amp;rsquo;s room for everyone. The Groups are located at key spots around the city for your convenience.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Treatment Clinic</title>
      <link>/services/treatment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:14:08 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/treatment/</guid>
      <description>Make an appointment to see one of our doctors.
Fresh Start Recovery Programme offers specialist addiction treatment (detox and relapse prevention) on Wednesdays and Saturdays (excluding long weekends). Treatments for sedative dependence are typically started on Fridays.
Addiction Medicine Specialist and Medical Director Dr George O&amp;rsquo;Neil MBBS, FAChAM, FRANZCOG, FROCOG, DDU, CitWA
Dr O&amp;rsquo;Neil is a Fellow of the Australian Chapter of Addiction Medicine within the Adult Medicine Division of the Royal Australian College of Physicians.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 17:55:17 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/contact/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start Recovery Programme ABN: 84 106 876 019
65 Townshend Road Subiaco Western Australia 6008  Ph: (08) 9381 1333 Fax: (08) 9388 7073  Email: info@freshstart.org.au

View Larger Map</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A Message from the CEO</title>
      <link>/news/2017/07/message/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2017/07/message/</guid>
      <description>On 16th June, Fresh Start celebrated 20 years of helping families with addictions. What Dr George O’Neil began in 1997 as a specialised service to mothers and babies struggling with addiction to heroin and methadone has grown steadily and now looks after more than 1000 men and women every year. We currently provide care and treatment for opiate, amphetamine, benzodiazepine and alcohol addictions. To date more than 11,000 people have been helped by Fresh Start in Subiaco.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Admission to the Northam Recovery Program</title>
      <link>/news/2017/07/nrp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2017/07/nrp/</guid>
      <description>At Fresh Start we recommend that our clients participate in a Rehabilitation Program after treatment. It removes those struggling with addiction from their old ways of life and places them into a facility that offers 24&amp;frasl;7 care. In-house recovery programs help to eliminate stress by removing the individual from temptation and reducing the chance of relapse.
Northam Recovery Program (NRP) offers a comprehensive residential program focused on men’s recovery. Residents will begin their journey at Northam Recovery Centre until they are able to graduate to The Hill a farm based centre 8kms from Northam.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Start graduate completes Law degree</title>
      <link>/news/2017/07/graduate/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2017/07/graduate/</guid>
      <description>The committed and brave life of Chris O&amp;rsquo;Donoghue illustrates the long, hard road a drug addict takes to drive out their cravings. In 2007 Chris arrived on Fresh Start’s doorstep in the depths of addiction, only recovering after three years of treatment. He went on to volunteer at Fresh Start and eventually became a paid employee. In 2010 he returned to his family and friends in Queensland. As Chris recounts,</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hepatitis Clinic Highlights</title>
      <link>/news/2017/07/highlights/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2017/07/highlights/</guid>
      <description>The past 12 months has been a very exciting time for our Hepatitis Clinic and we have successfully treated over 100 patients for Hepatitis C with the newly released, directly acting anti-viral tablets that are both well tolerated and highly effective. Dr Wendy Lawrence and specialist Hepatitis nurse Julie Stove work closely to provide the clinical support needed by the 55 people currently in treatment.
Streamlined services to clients offer:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>UWA clinical trial on Fresh Start&#39;s Smoking Cessation Spray</title>
      <link>/news/2017/07/trial/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/2017/07/trial/</guid>
      <description>The University of Western Australia is part-way through a clinical trial, testing a new Smoking Cessation Spray invented by Dr George O’Neil. A preliminary study involving ten Fresh Start clients indicated that the spray significantly reduces anxiety and the urge to smoke. These initial findings were promising enough to initiate a larger, randomized placebo-controlled trial.
Early participants in the trial have commented that “Using the active spray I felt much more chilled and didn’t even feel like having a cigarette” and “Since participating in the trial I feel way more confident about quitting smoking.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Our Approach Our Leadership Annual Overview Subscribe Accreditation Privacy Statement   Fresh Start Recovery Programme grew out of a commitment to help drug users and their families recover from drug dependence. Fresh Start concentrates on detox and developing a drug free lifestyle.
Fresh Start&amp;rsquo;s founder Dr George O&amp;rsquo;Neil performed his first addiction treatment in 1997. Dr O&amp;rsquo;Neil was motivated to help the community with its addiction problems while working as an obstetrician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accreditation</title>
      <link>/about/accreditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/accreditation/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start: A Licensed Day Hospital We are delighted to announce that after a year long accreditation process with the Health Department of Western Australia, the Fresh Start Clinic in Subiaco has been recognized as a Class B Day Hospital.
Chief Executive Officer Jeff Claughton said that “Fresh Start is thrilled to have achieved this milestone as it will enable us to ensure that patients continue to receive care in an improved environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Overview</title>
      <link>/about/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/overview/</guid>
      <description>Click to view our Annual Overview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Detoxification</title>
      <link>/services/detoxification/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/detoxification/</guid>
      <description>Make an appointment to see one of our doctors.
Detoxifying from opiates has some unpleasant symptoms including insomnia, restlessness, pain, fatigue and diarrhoea. If someone detoxifies with no medication, the process and its symptoms will last for 3 to 14 days, or even longer, depending on the amount and type of opiate the person has been using.
Fresh Start uses a form of accelerated opiate detox which significantly reduces the withdrawal period.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home</title>
      <link>/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/home/</guid>
      <description>Home page content goes here&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Services</title>
      <link>/services/services/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/services/services/</guid>
      <description>Treatment Clinic GP Clinic Detoxification Hepatitis C Treatment Mental Health Care Counselling Chaplaincy Housing Rehabilitation Support Groups   Sometimes abstinence alone isn’t enough to overcome addiction. That’s why Fresh Start Recovery Programme offers medical and allied health treatments for addiction.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscribe</title>
      <link>/about/subscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/subscribe/</guid>
      <description>Click to sign up to our publication mailing list.
For copies of our past publications or brochures please email us at info@freshstart.org.au.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>