<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Supports on Fresh Start</title>
    <link>/support/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Supports on Fresh Start</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Fresh Start</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:19:01 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/support/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Fresh Start Wish List</title>
      <link>/support/wishes/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:19:01 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/wishes/</guid>
      <description>Small Items for Northam Recovery Centre  Art supplies for the residents to use (e.g. paint, card, paint brushes).  Small Items for Harborne House  Board games Toiletries for patients (toothbrushes, toothpaste, soap, shampoo, deodorant) Non-perishable food items Bedding (e.g. doonas, doona covers, sheets, pillows, pillow cases).  Big Items for Harborne House  TV new kitchen.  Please contact us if you would like to donate any of these or if you have any other items you think would be useful to Fresh Start.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Volunteer</title>
      <link>/support/volunteer/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:18:52 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/volunteer/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start Recovery Programme is committed to excellent service to both our clients and the wider community. Delivering this service would not be possible without the help of our committed volunteers.
Among the valuable services our volunteers provide are:
 helping care for patients during their detox period helping transport patients assisting with administrative duties in the office preparing food for patients on treatment days taking part in busy bees to freshen up and maintain the residential housing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invite Us To Visit</title>
      <link>/support/visit/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:18:45 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/visit/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start would be delighted to visit your community group or church or come to a gathering in your home. We have a number of presentations that are suitable for different settings, such as:
 “Help us to help families with addictions” (a fundraising talk by our CEO) “Helping families avoid addictions” (presented by one of our senior staff) “Why do children from good families still get addicted?” (presented by one of our doctors).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Make a Bequest</title>
      <link>/support/bequest/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:18:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/bequest/</guid>
      <description>By making a bequest to Fresh Start Recovery Programme (a Deductible Gift Recipient and Registered Health Charity), you can help us to continue our work beyond your lifetime, offering a lasting contribution towards recovery from addictions and rebuilding families. Your bequest will play a vital role in supporting our treatment and rehabilitation services or ongoing research into development and improvement of medical procedures for addictions. When you include us in your Will, you are offering the gift of hope and a Fresh Start to some of the most vulnerable people in our community.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Donate</title>
      <link>/support/donate/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:18:26 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/donate/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start greatly appreciates the generous support we receive from individuals, the business community and various organisations. We are only able to continue our work through partnerships with organisations and individuals. Together we can offer a Fresh Start and the gift of hope for a drug-free future.
All donations over $2 are tax-deductible.
There are several ways you can offer financial support:
 Monthly Donation Make a monthly gift to Fresh Start and you will help heal families and individuals who have been torn apart by addictions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Northam Greeting Cards</title>
      <link>/support/cards/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:18:18 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/cards/</guid>
      <description>Residents at Northam Recovery Centre are creating unique, hand-made greeting cards as part of the Northam Art Program. These original art works can be used for any occasion!
Cards are for sale for $3.50 each or 10 cards for $30 plus packing and handling. (This includes envelopes.) Please contact the Northam Recovery Centre to order cards.
All funds raised go towards supporting the Northam Art Program as well as various leisure activities and excursions for residents on the road to recovery.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Support Us</title>
      <link>/support/support/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 29 Sep 2017 15:08:51 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/support/support/</guid>
      <description> Northam Greeting Cards Donate Make a Bequest Invite Us To Visit Volunteer Fresh Start Wish List    I wondered why somebody didn&amp;rsquo;t do something. Then I realized, I am somebody. &amp;ndash; Lily Tomlin
 </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>