<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Abouts on Fresh Start</title>
    <link>/about/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Abouts on Fresh Start</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>Fresh Start</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:34:35 +0800</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/about/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Beliefs and Values</title>
      <link>/about/beliefs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:34:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/beliefs/</guid>
      <description>The Fresh Start Statement of Belief embodies a primary commitment of the organisation: Good Christian teaching.
Our Christian Beliefs  The Nature and Character of God We believe in one God, who has existed forever as Father, Son and Holy Spirit in a community of pure and eternal love.
 The Creation of Humanity Men and women were created in God&amp;rsquo;s likeness with God-given dignity and worth in order to know, love and serve him forever.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Statement</title>
      <link>/about/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:34:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/privacy/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start Recovery Programme (&amp;ldquo;Fresh Start&amp;rdquo;) is legally bound by the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth). We are committed to protecting and securing the privacy and confidentiality of your personal information.
Fresh Start must apply the National Privacy Principles in Schedule 3 of the Privacy Act 1988 (Cth) that came into effect on 21 December 2001. These principles relate to collection, use, disclosure and security of your personal information, as well as access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Board</title>
      <link>/about/leadership/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:34:35 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/leadership/</guid>
      <description>G.A.D (Sandy) Clarkson - Chairman Sandy is an Accountant with a private CPA Accounting Practice. He has worked in the private sector for most of his life with stints in the WA State Government and in Local Government as Councillor and Deputy Mayor of the town of Mosman Park.
He has been associated with Fresh Start Recovery Programme for almost 15 years as a volunteer, Director and Chairman.
Alison Petrie Alison is the Managing Director of professional conference management company, EECW Pty Ltd based in Nedlands WA.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Our Approach</title>
      <link>/about/approach/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2017 18:34:23 +0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/approach/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start’s approach to helping people with addictions is sometimes known as the PHREE model:
 Physiology Housing Relationships Education Employment  Physiology Our programs treat the physical cravings of drug addiction. Our follow up and other medical services such as our GP Clinic and Hepatitis C program support the general health of patients.
Housing Many drug users who come to Fresh Start depend on other users for a place to live.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About Us</title>
      <link>/about/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/about/</guid>
      <description>Our Approach Our Leadership Annual Overview Subscribe Accreditation Privacy Statement   Fresh Start Recovery Programme grew out of a commitment to help drug users and their families recover from drug dependence. Fresh Start concentrates on detox and developing a drug free lifestyle.
Fresh Start&amp;rsquo;s founder Dr George O&amp;rsquo;Neil performed his first addiction treatment in 1997. Dr O&amp;rsquo;Neil was motivated to help the community with its addiction problems while working as an obstetrician.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accreditation</title>
      <link>/about/accreditation/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/accreditation/</guid>
      <description>Fresh Start: A Licensed Day Hospital We are delighted to announce that after a year long accreditation process with the Health Department of Western Australia, the Fresh Start Clinic in Subiaco has been recognized as a Class B Day Hospital.
Chief Executive Officer Jeff Claughton said that “Fresh Start is thrilled to have achieved this milestone as it will enable us to ensure that patients continue to receive care in an improved environment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Annual Overview</title>
      <link>/about/overview/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/overview/</guid>
      <description>Click to view our Annual Overview.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Subscribe</title>
      <link>/about/subscribe/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2017 07:51:49 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/subscribe/</guid>
      <description>Click to sign up to our publication mailing list.
For copies of our past publications or brochures please email us at info@freshstart.org.au.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>